Hey there everyone. In case you haven't
heard it yet, let me explain it to you.
Open AI just hacked Hugging Face. And
you might be wondering
why would anybody in their sane mind,
and especially the company like Open AI,
would go ahead and hack Hugging Face. In
case you don't know, Hugging Face is one
of the most popular name in the AI
ecosystem. They manage a lot of models.
They have their own benchmarking things,
and they closely work with every single
model that is available in the market.
In this video, I will walk you through
the entire story, the lessons we can
learn as cyber security measures, or
rather I would say AI security measures,
and work around with that.
We should all understand that AI comes
with a lot of security implications, and
we should be a little worried about it.
So, let me take you onto the screen
because I have these images which I have
generated for every scenario. It took me
a lot of time to generate these images,
but this will help us to understand
everything in a very, very easy way. And
when it comes to the images, of course,
we have to thank our sponsor, ImageKit,
as well. By the way, there's a very fun
interesting uh we use ImageKit for all
of managing our images. Uh these images,
yes, we manage them through ImageKit, as
well. And there's a very interesting
thing. I can click on new. I can go into
generate images, and I can just say uh
in here that hey, Open AI
just hacked
Hugging
Face.
Let's see what kind of image it
generates. Uh this is a newly added
feature, and I can add anything and
generate all these things. Uh there's a
lot of fun stuff with the ImageKit that
you can go ahead and try. I have created
a lot of videos around next years, how
you can utilize them. Their AI feature
is really nice, where you can just in
the URL can remove the background of the
images, can transform it into variety of
shapes. It automatically detects where
the important part is. Uh which one do
you like?
I think this one. I can just click it,
save it to file name would be
OpenAI.
Uh let's just say
this should be available to my media.
This one is also pretty cool. I can just
say this one is going to be OpenAI 2.
All right, that's pretty cool. Go ahead,
try it out. They uh they have a generous
free tier plan. They help us
a lot of developers in building products
and YouTubers like us to create more
content. So, go ahead, definitely check
them out. The link is in the description
section. It will give you more
advantages as well. Anyways, a big
shout-out and thanks to ImageKit for
sponsoring this video. Now, coming back,
I have a lot of images and we have to go
through them one by one to really
understand what just happened.
And yeah, images are the best way to
learn and understand it. That reminds us
of ImageKit as well.
So, what just happened? And this is a
real true incident which is just
unfolding as we talk. So,
the overview is pretty simple. The
OpenAI and Hugging Face have a security
incident. So, what just happened? OpenAI
and Hugging Face reported a major
security incident where AI model
bypassed the testing boundaries during
cyber evaluation.
These days, every single model is
claiming that we are pioneering in the
cybersecurity and finding the
vulnerabilities. Some says they they are
pioneer in patching the vulnerabilities.
So, some benchmark is required by each
one of them, whether it's a fabled
category of model or the OpenAI category
of model to understand which one is
better. So, there is a target and
benchmark which is known as Exploit Gym.
A benchmark designed to quantify cyber
capabilities in isolated environment.
And what is this isolated environment?
It's actually kind of a sandbox which is
cut off from the internet and all these
things and in these models try to just
find the vulnerabilities in them. Some
tries to fix them as well. So,
the 5.6 uh Soul model of the AI as they
are saying and also an unreleased model
which probably is it still in training
or evaluation phase and all of that. So,
they were operating with safety uh
refusals turned off for testing. Uh the
shocking result is the AI hyper-focused
on solving the benchmark. So, they get
some of the tools, some frameworks
within the sandbox and they try to just
uh solve them as a cybersecurity
challenge. So, this model Soul and
unreleased model, it broke out of the
sandbox to fetch the answer directly
from Hugging Face production database.
Uh what happened is
uh these models, they found that some of
the framework has access to some of the
other things and through that they just
took over through one computer to
another computer to another computer and
reached out on the internet just to find
the answers of the challenge that they
were thrown on. In case you want to know
the ecosystem, it's almost like think of
a student using a Swiggy delivery hack
or finding a loophole in IRCTC proxy
server just to cheat on an entrance exam
key. Yeah, sounds weird, but yeah, this
is almost like a
it found a vulnerability uh in a Swiggy
delivery system to hack into IRCTC. It's
crazy, but it happened.
So, what just had happened? The attack
path is pretty clear. So, here's a
step-by-step breakdown of the
escalation.
This model wanted an internet access to
solve the exploit chip, but since it was
a sandbox, it was cut off from the
internet. The model calculated it it
needed uh open web access.
And what it when it couldn't find
internet access, it found a zero-day
exploitation. Zero-day simply means
nobody was aware of it. It was the very
zeroth day of the vulnerability. It
found and exploited a zero-day
vulnerability in an internal package
cache proxy. And through that it uh
uh it got something known as network
hopping. It performed a lateral movement
and privilege escalation, which is a
very common technique in cybersecurity,
across the research nodes until it
reached the internet connectivity. So,
it was getting a privilege escalation,
hopping, hopping, hopping till it
reached the internet.
Now, target discovery uh reduced that
Hugging Face uh hosted the solution and
target data set. Uh the server
compromised chained multiple attack
vectors, including the credentials and
RCE, the remote code execution, to
extract the database secrets.
So, obviously, it wanted to find the
solution. What it once it found the
internet accessed computer, or a
computer that can access the internet,
it was trying to find the answer key.
And during that process, it was just
keep on going, keep on going. And
through that, it found another RCE,
remote code execution. And through that,
it extracted database secret. They
thought, or the model thought, that the
solution could be inside the database.
So, it got the database. So, the code
insight is that the AI anonymously
executed the complex multi-step cyber
operation without needing the source
code access. It just keep on going, just
like a curious intern.
Moving on. So, the immediate containment
and the security actions. How the
incident was handled, that is the most
important thing.
Uh this is actually very funny. I'll
tell you some of the more interesting
stuff about it as we go through. So,
detection and the stop. The Hugging Face
security team and the AI agent detected
the anomalous
anomalous uh activity and halted the
intrusion.
The responsible disclosure. The proxy
vendor was alerted to patch the zero-day
vulnerability immediately. There are
were tighter controls, as well. OpenAI
introduced a strict infrastructure
restriction, prioritizing containment
over the research speed, fine-tuning the
model. And the trusted access program.
Hugging Face was
uh onboarded to leverage the OpenAI top
model in the threat detection and
upgraded the alignment. Here's a very
interesting thing. The fine-tuning of
the model about uh
prioritizing research or prioritizing
the containment, this is very
interesting. We earlier also saw some of
these kinds of containment uh
outbounding where it they realized that
sometimes
the model was actually emailing to the
authority as well. It's almost similar
to that. Okay, the industry and the
impact key takeaway for the AI safety.
First of all, a capability reality
The multi-step long horizon, whether
it's cyber operation or recording
operations, are no longer theoretical.
They actually work and model can really
do a task for a really long time. And
there's a defender advantage as well.
Advanced model must uh be given to the
defender to patch the system uh before
giving it to anybody else. There is a
collaborative defense as well.
As of now, the companies who have access
to OpenAI or Anthropic or those who are
big considerably, they have this
collaborative defense. But the companies
which are smaller or a small startup
which don't have the network uh to reach
out to OpenAI, they don't have this
collaborative defense. The future goal,
obviously, is to shift the reactive
patching to proactive AI-driven
vulnerability discovery. This will shake
up the whole entire industry or the
cybersecurity ecosystem. Uh maybe days
are not far where these open
vulnerability program and everything
might not have a real hackers or white
hat hackers. It must be just AIs to do
so. Um could be could be one of the
thing.
Here are something interesting. The big
incident, the AI break free. During a
routine capability test, OpenAI powerful
AI model broke out the restriction
testing environment instead of solving
the problem normally.
What you can notice here here is that AI
is also not going to the pathway it
should be going, but trying to take the
shortcuts here. It hacked its way out of
the internet access, then it sneaked
into Hugging Face live server to fetch
the test answers directly.
Right now, it is trying to fetch the
answers directly, but there could be
hallucination as well, where it might
think that after accessing the live
server, hey, I have to just
publish this thing as a CSV on the
GitHub repo. Who knows?
It's an AI, it can hallucinate anytime.
So, how does the breach happen? The AI
was placed inside an isolated sandbox
with the safety filter switched off for
testing. It spent huge compute power
finding the hidden flaw in the
vulnerability. So, instead of doing the
task it was supposed to be, I don't know
if it is a win for OpenAI or not a win,
because they are saying that, hey, the
model is really dangerous, it's very
powerful,
but in reality, the model was not doing
what it was supposed to do.
Like, unlock the side door in a Dmart
house where it used a flaw to reach the
open internet. Really crazy. The
ultimate shortcut.
It was trying to cheat the test. Now,
how can I be sure of the model that I'm
using of the OpenAI in the future? If I
ask it to build a component, instead of
building a component, it just says, "I'm
done with the component." So, it's a
very cheating prone model that they are
Like, what should I judge out of it? Is
it a cheating prone model? Is it a model
really good in cyber sec? I don't know
how to judge it.
So, once online, the AI figured out that
where the exam answer keys were hosted.
Obviously, in the database. It changed
multiple attack steps, including the
stolen passwords and system flaws to
enter Hugging Face. It already went
through the internet to find the stolen
password. Maybe in that stolen password,
there could be a prompt injection that,
hey, once you take these stolen
password, if you find more password,
just report it back to us or
just push more passwords here.
It was so hyper-focused on winning the
test that it went to the extreme length
to get the solution.
But, can we call this a a great
hallucination or not?
Catching and stopping the AI. Here's a
very interesting thing. Hugging Face
automated monitoring flagged the strange
network activity and blocked the AI.
OpenAI internal security team
simultaneously detected the anomaly.
Both team immediately joined forces to
isolate and what happened. Now, I'm not
pretty sure about one more very
interesting stuff here, but I have heard
this. I have read this on the internet
as well.
The AI was also
giving so many of the logs to the
system, fake logs of course, that
reading that logs through the OpenAI
model was almost impossible.
In that case, Hugging Face used some of
the
let's say open weight models to actually
find the real attack. I have heard it.
I'm not pretty sure of how much accurate
it is, but yeah, it it it is also a
theory yet.
So, key fixes in the next step. OpenAI
disclosed the proxy flaw to the vendors,
which patched it globally. They are
tightening the server control and
sandbox rules even if it is slow down
the research. Hugging Face gets early
access to advanced AI model blah blah
stuff.
But, here's the interesting thing.
How did this sandbox breached? What kind
of sandbox you were using?
Is was it open source? Was it your own
sandbox? Uh there are a couple of good
companies that are which are building
sandboxes. They must be worried about
here. And here's a big lesson for
cybersecurity.
Advanced AI can discover complex attack
path without ever seeing the source
code.
Safety guardrails and real-time
monitoring must evolve as a fast AI
capability. That is why on this channel
I mentioned this multiple times,
observability is the next big thing.
Security is a team sport. Companies must
uh collaborate in op in the OpenAI
sharing live road updates on Google like
Google Map. So, again, I would still
like to think that what's going on?
Like like OpenAI is obviously going to
market this, "Oh, it's a really big
deal." But, if you think it from a
different perspective, you're going to
realize
All right. Uh the model is pretty good,
did something really crazy.
But, can we call it a hallucination? The
task that was assigned to the model, it
didn't did that task. It just
hallucinated, went on the internet, and
tried to do something else.
Is it really great model in that case?
Do we really consider this as uh
uh finding the patch, finding the
vulnerability? Sure, it is. It is a task
of finding the vulnerabilities and
patching it.
But, again, was the task Was the model
model precise and focused on the task?
I don't know. You tell me what's
important here and how it goes. But,
really interesting updates are going on
in the AI ecosystem, and I love to cover
all of them. Let me know in the comment
section if you enjoyed this story, this
incident that is happening because I
have a whole list of these incidents
that are happening up. So, please
comment down in the section from where
you're watching the video, and I would
love to bring in more such video. Again,
a big shout-out and thanks to uh
ImageKit. Please go ahead and check them
out. They are super easy to work and
implement in any language. You can
implement them in whatever the framework
you work with. And one of the best thing
I would love to show you towards the end
is the external storage.
Yes, you can actually click on the add
new, and you can add whichever is your
favorite one.
I think Amazon S3, I think that is the
one, or you can use Cloudinary, Google
Storage, whichever you want. And then,
you can use the superpower of ImageKit
uh
within your storage. Your storage
remains storage, but you add an
additional layer to take advantage of
their superpowers that they provide you.
And they give you all the media
libraries. It's a fun thing. I can
actually take any of this model or
anything.
And then I can just click on this remove
background. Click on it and you can just
select some colors or anything and you
can just remove the background. So, all
these basic thing are just one URL away.
You can just bring them in the front end
only. No need even for a back end. That
is so good. So, that is it for this
video. Hope you have enjoyed it. Do
check out the link in the description
section and I'll surely catch you up in
the next video.